<resources>
    <string name="app_name">30 Days Fitness</string>
    <string name="program1">Starting Strength</string>
    <string name="program1desc">The Starting Strength Novice Program can be broken down into two workout days, Day A and Day B.
        The entire body is worked each session. As the trainee progresses through the program, Days A and B are slightly modified
        to take into account the adaptations in the body of the lifter.</string>
    <string name="program2">Judo: Beginner Strength</string>
    <string name="program2desc">This beginner program is aimed to build strength for judokas. It is meant to start off with and to progress to the intermediate circuit.</string>
    <string name="program3">3 Day Split</string>
    <string name="program3desc">A 3 day workout split can be a great way to plan your workout week if you’re pressed for time or don’t
        want to be in the gym 5 times a week. The different variations of a 3 day workout split are arguably amongst the most used by
        gym athletes all around the world.</string>
    <string name="programdesc1">The Starting Strength Program is designed for novice lifters.
    This program takes advantage of \"newbie gains\" by adding 10 pounds to the squat after 2 times it\'s performed,
        15-20 lbs to the deadlift the first couple times, and 10 lbs the next several times it\'s performed.
        For the bench press/shoulder press and the power clean you increment by 5lbs. This program is designed for 3 days a week M/W/F.</string>
    <string name="phase1">Phase 1</string>
    <string name="phase2">Phase 2</string>
    <string name="phase3">Phase 3</string>
    <string name="dayA">Day A</string>
    <string name="dayB">Day B</string>
    <string name="squat">Squats</string>
    <string name="squatdesc">1. Stand with feet a little wider than hip width, toes facing front.\n
    2. Drive your hips back—bending at the knees and ankles and pressing your knees slightly open—as you…\n
    3. Sit into a squat position while still keeping your heels and toes on the ground, chest up and shoulders back.\n
    4. Strive to eventually reach parallel, meaning knees are bent to a 90-degree angle.\n
    5. Press into your heels and straighten legs to return to a standing upright position.</string>
    <string name="deadlift">Deadlifts</string>
    <string name="deadliftdesc">1. Stand with your mid-foot under the barbell\n
    2. Bend over and grab the bar with a shoulder-width grip\n
    3. Bend your knees until your shins touch the bar\n
    4. Lift your chest up and straighten your lower back\n
    5. Take a big breath, hold it, and stand up with the weight</string>
    <string name="chinup">Chin-Ups</string>
    <string name="chinupdesc">1. Stand with your arms shoulder-width apart and reach up to grab the overhead bar. Make sure to use an underhand grip — so your palms face toward you.\n
    2. Brace your abdominal muscles to create tension throughout your body — this increases your stability as you move.\n
    3. Pull yourself up from your stationary position until your chin is above the bar. Your legs should remain as still as possible and your neck should be in a neutral position, with your head facing forward.\n
    4. Pause for a moment at the top.\n
    5. Then slowly lower yourself back down. Force yourself to move slowly during this portion to maximize your gains from this exercise. </string>
    <string name="bench">Bench Press</string>
    <string name="benchdesc">1. Lie on the bench with your eyes under the bar\n
    2. Grab the bar with a medium grip-width (thumbs around the bar!)\n
    3. Unrack the bar by straightening your arms\n
    4. Lower the bar to your mid-chest\n
    5. Press the bar back up until your arms are straight</string>
    <string name="shoulderp">Shoulder Press</string>
    <string name="shoulderpdesc">1. Stand with the bar on your front shoulders, and your hands next to your shoulders\n
    2. Press the bar over your head, until it’s balanced over your shoulders and mid-foot\n
    3. Lock your elbows at the top, and shrug your shoulders to the ceiling.</string>
    <string name="clean">Power Cleans</string>
    <string name="cleandesc">Since this is a complicated excercise we will do it in phases.\n
    </string>
    <string name="deadclean">Deadlift/Power Clean</string>
    <string name="deadcleandesc">At this point you’ve become strong enough to pull enough weight that we limit deadlift and cleaning frequency.</string>
    <string name="dowelhinge">Dowel Hip Hinge on Incline board</string>
    <string name="dowelhingedesc">1. Stand on an incline board.\n
        2.Shift your weight to your heels and push your hips back towards the wall behind you while you hinge forward at the hips. Think about sticking your butt out behind you. As you hinge, the dowel should not lose contact with those three points. If it does, you know you’re doing the move incorrectly.\n
        3. Lower your torso until it’s midway between vertical and parallel to the floor. Pause. Keep a slight bend in your knees during the downward and upward phase.\n
        4. Reverse the movement by contracting your glutes and pushing your hips forward and upward to return to the starting position. </string>
    <string name="deadliftjump">Deadlift to toes - to jump</string>
    <string name="deadliftjumpdesc">1. Do a regular deadlift and finish on your toes/ball of your foot \n
    2. Set the bar down in a controlled fashion. \n
    3. Do a regular deadlift with a jump</string>
    <string name="lungeRow">Barbell bent over row from lunge</string>
    <string name="lungeRowDesc">1. Grip bar tightly to your hips.\n
    2. Go into a bent over lunge position.\n
    3. Set bar down then pull to the waist.</string>
    <string name="deepsquatrow">Mid cable row in deep squat</string>
    <string name="deepsquatrowdesc">1. Position cable in hip height.\n
    2. Go down in a deeep squat position.\n
    3. Pull cable in a rowing motion.</string>
    <string name="zombiesquat">Zombie Squat on incline board</string>
    <string name="zombiesquatdesc">1. Stand on incline board. \n
    2. Place the bar right in front of your shoulder muscles, once the bar is stable stick your arms out like a zombie.\n
    3. With chest up go as low as you can preferrably to 90 degrees.\n
    4. Reset to standing</string>
    <string name="armpulltowaist">High cable straight arm pull to waist in hinge hold</string>
    <string name="armpulltowaistdesc">1. Set up your attachment of choice (i.e. straight bar, wide grip bar, or rope attachment) to a cable or lat pulldown machine and grip the attachment with an overhand (palms facing down) or neutral shoulder-width grip (palms facing in).\n
        2. Then step back from the machine and straighten your arms. Keep your chest up and pull your shoulders down and back for better shoulder positioning. Brace your anterior core.\n
        3. Hinge your butt back and lean forward to a 35 to a 45-degree angle, feeling a slight stretch in your lats with your arms up in the top position.\n
        4. Keeping straight arms, pull the bar down to your thighs focusing on pulling your shoulder blades down and back. Pause for a second.\n
        5. Then slowly bring it back up, keeping your elbows in place, and raise the bar until you feel a stretch in your lats.\n
        6. Repeat for reps. </string>
    <string name="shoulderpfromknee">Shoulder Press from kneeling</string>
    <string name="shoulderpfromkneedesc">1. Find a stable half kneeling position with the knee at 90 degrees.\n
        2. Start with the dumbbell at the shoulder, with the elbow facing slightly away from the body.\n
        3. Press the dumbbell overhead and lock the elbow to move through the full range of motion.\n
        4. Move back to the starting position with control. Do not let the weight pull you out of position.</string>
    <string name="expand_button_content_description">See more or less information about an exercise.</string>


</resources>